<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phil and El Camino de Santiago</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Phil and El Camino de Santiago</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>0: Introduction</title>
      <link>/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>In May of 2017, while working in a Title I Elementary school in New Hampshire, I read a little fable called “Rebirth” by Kaval Ravikant.
The main character, Amit, is unable to return home after the death of his estranged father. He wanders, lost and filled with pain and grief, and is led to the Camino de Santiago. There, he meets many travelers and pilgrims. Some are lost and searching for answers, others are running from their past, but all have a story to share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1: Beginnings</title>
      <link>/posts/beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/beginnings/</guid>
      <description>The Camino de Santiago is a network of pilgrimage routes that lead to the city of Santiago de Compostela in Northwestern Spain, where the Saint James is rumored to be buried. The most popular route is the Camino Frances. It begins at Saint-Jean-Pied-de-Port in Southern France, a small city located north of the Pyrenees, and totals about 500 miles across to Santiago de Compostela. Many walk for spiritual and religious reasons; I walk in search of myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2: First Ascent</title>
      <link>/posts/firstascent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/firstascent/</guid>
      <description>I woke to the sound of creaking bunk beds, rustling backpacks, and clanking poles. 5:30 a.m. Time to go. I put my boots on, packed my sleeping bag, and went downstairs.
Small talk of good weather and stellar walking conditions. Free bread was served, though it was as stiff as stones. Luckily we were also provided with butter and peach marmalade. I devour as much of the bread as my mouth could muster and went on my way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3: Tea</title>
      <link>/posts/tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tea/</guid>
      <description>A Poem Through the window I see Sun-bathed flowers and untouched rock,
Blades of grass and untrodden walks,
Endless possibility.
I ask of you Time
To yield your determined hand
So I may dance forever with
Infinity.
–09.09.17
 I ran into Matilde and Franca while departing from Roncesvalles. They were headed in the opposite direction, back toward the albergue.
“Phiiiiilll! Hey we’re gonna make some tea! Would you like to join us?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4: Möge die Straße</title>
      <link>/posts/strasse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/strasse/</guid>
      <description>We are quick to fill the silence with our unnecessary words and thoughts. When &amp;gt;quiet presents itself, welcome it with an open heart. Beauty is found within &amp;gt;stillness and silence. We are found within stillness and silence.
 &amp;hellip; Another gray and rainy day. We slept in and started walking at 8am. After the deep and enlightening conversations of yesterday, we decided it would be best to walk in solitude today –– together, but left to the vicinity of our own worlds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5: The Cusp of Time and Infinity</title>
      <link>/posts/cusp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cusp/</guid>
      <description>In the morning we walked to Pamplona, our first city. I ran into Maria and chatted with her for a brief moment before running off with the girls to get breakfast. I didn’t know it then, but that would be my final conversation with her. One thing the Camino teaches you, by nature of necessity, is how to let go. Of people, places, your past.
We stopped at a small bakery near the entrance of the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6: Sunsets and Soulmates</title>
      <link>/posts/suns-souls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/suns-souls/</guid>
      <description>“Phil! I have a genius idea. You’re really going to like it.”
On the 12th day, M, S, and I went to the top of a hill to catch the sunset. We sifted through an amber field of dry grass and settled ourselves in a small circular clearing. The sky was cloudless, a cool breeze was present. We talked for awhile, about what I can’t remember, but I felt wonderfully alive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7: Goodbye</title>
      <link>/posts/goodbye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/goodbye/</guid>
      <description>Day 15. We’re sitting amid a messy clump of dining tables in the main plaza of Burgos, sipping on wine and eating tapas. The patrons and pilgrims look happy, the cathedral towers above us. I look up and wonder, Is there such a thing as a good goodbye?
M looks content and tells her squirrel joke again. I try to listen, but my attention has been seized by the fact that she is leaving tonight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8: Gone</title>
      <link>/posts/gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gone/</guid>
      <description>I have sunken into the depths of an all-too-familiar melancholy.
She is gone. I am alone. My emotions are swinging to the erratic cadence of an unforgiving grandfather clock.
 I’m fine. I’m fine. I’m fine. I’m not. 
I miss the jade of her eyes, those luminescent opals I so often lose myself in. The ease of her smile, it was always able to bring about my own. The way she plucked those juicy blackberries from their thorny brambles, always a tad out of reach, the hem of her shirt lifting ever so slightly in the process, revealing the contours of a titillating landscape I secretly wished to explore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9: An Ode to the Road</title>
      <link>/posts/ode/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ode/</guid>
      <description>Each and every day, I wake and walk with the sun behind me.
It starts low, climbing over hillsides, rising slowly.
It finds its temporary place amid the sky
and begins to color the Meseta.
Front and center a shadow grows.
It looks at me with indifference – a mirror of my darker side.
Fear, insecurity, doubt,
The manifestation of my demons.
Each and every day, I wake and walk to confront these demons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10: Journal Entries, Day 17 - 20</title>
      <link>/posts/journal17-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/journal17-20/</guid>
      <description>September 23, 2017 - Day 17 We are always on the cusp of collapse and redemption. Do we choose to rise, or fall?
Stories = meaning. The mind is a meaning-making machine.
Words and stories delight me. They also have the power to change people’s lives – they certainly have changed mine. We are the narrators.
Though that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we&amp;rsquo;re always accurate.
&amp;hellip; Today, a group of Americans invited me to their table at dinner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11: A Sea of Stars</title>
      <link>/posts/stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/stars/</guid>
      <description>Day 21 4:30am. I inch out from my sleeping bag like a slug, careful not to disturb the others in the room. I pack my things and head downstairs. Pauline and Morgan are already awake. We’re late.
My eyes are crusty. I wolf down a prepacked sandwich – chorizo and cheese – with yogurt. Pauline makes us some coffee. Bland, but it will do. Shoes on, rucksacks shouldered, we’re on the move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12: Journal Entries, Day 22 - 24</title>
      <link>/posts/journal22-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/journal22-24/</guid>
      <description>September 28, 2017 - Day 22  To be yourself–
Easy to say, hard to do.
What we think is not ours.
What we believe is shaped by others.
The only thing we own is
what we feel.
Our inner compass, the way we connect with
The outer world; only we can see and touch and
Feel the way we do. Never lose it.
Never let it go.
 &amp;hellip; Met Enrico and Sia today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13: The Iron Cross</title>
      <link>/posts/ironcross/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ironcross/</guid>
      <description>October 1st, 2017 - Day 25 Dawn. A ridge of silhouettes and gray clouds amid a colorless expanse. A string of headlamps clambering up a mountain. At the top, an iron cross.
The autumnal air invigorates me, my legs are weightless. I pass several pilgrims. Shanti is up ahead. I reach him and he smiles at me. We climb through the dark together, delighting in the thrill of ascension. The Spaniard and I are at home here in the highlands of Galicia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14: Letters to a Camino Soulmate</title>
      <link>/posts/letters-soulmate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/letters-soulmate/</guid>
      <description>These are the letters M and I wrote to each other after she was gone. They might give you a better picture of my Camino experience. Writing to her was always a highlight. Sorry for the grammar.
&amp;hellip; September 21, 2017  I just realized I did not give you my email. Safe travels! Thank &amp;gt;you for everything. –Phil
 &amp;hellip; September 23, 2017  Yesterday, as I walked away from Burgos, it clicked: you were &amp;gt;gone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15: Letters Worth Czeching Out</title>
      <link>/posts/letters-czech/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/letters-czech/</guid>
      <description>I wrote these letters to my friend, S, from the Czech Republic. Including them because they might help to create a better picture of my experience. He had joined M and I a few days before M left. These letters were written afterwards. &amp;hellip;
September 23, 2017  Hey it&amp;rsquo;s Phil.
I walked to Hontanas yesterday from Burgos (about 30 km). It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful village worth staying at. Today I&amp;rsquo;m walking to Itero de Vega, about 21 km.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16: Santiago</title>
      <link>/posts/santiago/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/santiago/</guid>
      <description>“How we spend our days is, of course, how we spend our lives.” –Annie Dillard
  &amp;hellip;  October 8, 2017 - Day 31 Pedrouzo, Spain.
In 20 kilometers, I will reach Santiago de Compostela. The anticipation has left me dreamless. Ali and Karen are fast asleep. Hope to see them again soon. I pack my things and make a quiet exit.
It’s dark out. Cars lie dormant under the hazy hue of flickering streetlights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17: The Final Goodbye</title>
      <link>/posts/final-goodbye/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/final-goodbye/</guid>
      <description>I arrived in Belgium late in the afternoon. The weather was exceptional: half-clouded skies with no reservation of sunlight, a perfect balance of cool and warm. I exited from the train station and hoisted myself against a tall statue, eagerly looking for my squirrelly Belgium. 15 minutes had passed before I noticed her standing only 20 meters behind me, clothed in a hoodie and a black leather jacket, gray faded jeans and the tall boots of an amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18: Home</title>
      <link>/posts/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 06:09:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/home/</guid>
      <description>After Belgium, I spent a night in Prague and took a bus to Hungary the next morning. I stayed there for 10 days with E, the Hungarian woman I had a crush on in the beginning of this whole adventure.
It felt strange, to be back in the swing of normalcy. As if such a thing was possible.
There was no bitterness or resentment toward M. Actually, I was alarmed at how fast I was “moving on”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>